Guide to the Everett and Evelyn Ortner papers and photographs ARC.306
Brooklyn Historical Society
- Series 3: Everett and Evelyn Ortner personal papers, 1900-2012; 43747
  - Sub-series 3.6: Address books, circa 1960s-2000s; 43515; 0.1 Linear Feet in one folder
    The sub-series contains the Ortner's address books, dating from circa 1960s to 2000s.
    - Address books, circa 1960s-2000s; 43516 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Sub-series 3.7: Daily diaries, 1968-2009; 43517; 0.9 Linear Feet in three folders and one small box
    The sub-series consists of daily diaries that track the day-to-day affairs of the Ortners, dating from 1968 to 2009.
    - Daily diaries and notes, 1968, 1974; 43518 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Daily diaries (2 folders), 1981-1985; 43519 (Box 14, Folder 1-2)
    - Daily diaries (36 diaries), 1985-2009; 43520 (Box 15, Folder -)
  - Sub-series 3.8: Personal computer, 2000s-2012; 44102; 1.16 Linear Feet in one personal computer
    Conditions Governing Access
    This computer is currently unprocessed and unavailable to researchers.
    The collection includes one personal computer that belonged to the Ortners from the 2000s to 2012.
    - Personal computer, 2000s-2012; 65831 (Item Personal computer (1 of 1), Item -)
- Series 4: Brooklyn and Historic Preservation photographs, circa 1880s-2002; 43749
  The series contains photographs related to Brooklyn and historic preservation in a variety of formats, dating from circa 1880s to 2002. Formats include prints, slides, negatives, and glass plate negatives. The series includes original photograghs by EHO, copy photographs of historic images used by EHO in lectures, and a small amount of original photographs taken by other photographers.
  Additional photographs taken by the Ortners can be found in Sub-series 3.1: Personal papers, memorabilia, and photographs.
  The series is organized into three sub-series:
  Sub-series 4.1: Brooklyn and Historic Preservation prints and negatives
  Sub-series 4.2: Brooklyn, Historic Preservation, and personal negatives
  Sub-series 4.3: Brooklyn and Historic Preservation slides
  - Sub-series 4.1: Brooklyn and Historic Preservation prints and negatives, circa 1880s-2002; 43918; 6.14 Linear Feet in one manuscript box, four flat boxes, two glass slide boxes, five folders, and three oversize folders
    Arranged chronologically
    The sub-series contains original photograghs by EHO, copy photographs of historic images used by EHO in lectures, and a small amount of original photographs taken by other photographers. The photographs date from circa 1881 to 2002. The sub-series includes prints, negatives (mostly sized 4" x 5"), lithographic prints, two stereocards, four glass-plate negatives, and one glass lantern slide. They primarily document buildings in the Brooklyn neighborhoods of Park Slope, Flatbush, and Prospect Park South. It includes photographs related to the Brownstone Revival Comittee, the Back to the City Conference, and Brooklyn Union Gas Company's Cinderella projects. Of note are a set of interior and exterior photographs of Prospect Park's Litchfield Villa.
    - View of St. Paul's Church and the Broadway Stages, N.Y. 1831, circa 1881; 44122 (Box 72, Folder -)
    - Olde New York photographs and research, circa 1880s-2002; 43885 (Box 47, Folder 12)
      Includes stereocards
    - Connecting New York and Brooklyn by the Electric Trolley. Finishing the Great Work at the New York Terminus of the Brooklyn Bridge., circa 1898; 49403 (Box 75, Folder -)
    - "Bird's-eye View of the Greater New York" by Hughson Hawley print, circa 1900s; 49419 (Box 76, Folder -)
    - Ports and terminals glass-plate negatives, circa 1910s; 44084 (Box Oversize Glass Negative box, Folder -)
      Includes the second 3rd Avenue Bridge (1868), Marginal Street at Pier 11 (1911), and St. George Ferry Terminal perspective drawing by Carrere and Hastings
    - Pier 4, E.R. and Canal Boat Basin - Panorama - Oversize glass-plate negative, circa 1910s; 49429 (Box 77, Folder -)
    - Nielsen's Havana cigar store (209 West 48th Street, New York) glass lantern slide, circa 1920s; 44085 (Box Glass Slide box, Folder -)
    - Panoramic View of the North Side of Forty-Second Street from Fifth to Lexington Avenues 1876, 1922; 49468 (Cabinet Flat file A, Drawer 1)
    - Ports and terminals negatives and prints, 1942-circa 1970s; 43886 (Box 47, Folder 13)
    - Park Slope historical copy negatives (4"x5"), circa 1960s; 43887 (Box 47, Folder 14)
    - Unidentified street scene print, circa 1960s; 49421 (Box 76, Folder -)
    - Litchfield Villa prints on board (1 of 2), circa 1965; 43888 (Box 47, Folder 15)
      V1974.12
    - Litchfield Villa prints on board (2 of 2), circa 1965; 43889 (Box 48, Folder 1)
    - Litchfield Villa prints, circa 1965; 43890 (Box 48, Folder 2)
    - Litchfield Villa contact sheets, circa 1965; 43891 (Box 48, Folder 3)
    - Park Slope photographs, circa 1960s-1970s; 43892 (Box 48, Folder 4)
    - Brownstone photographs, circa 1960s-1970s; 43893 (Box 48, Folder 5)
      Possibly used for Park Slope Historic District designation
    - Women in Victorian dress photographs, circa 1960s-1970s; 43894 (Box 48, Folder 6)
    - Brownstones and other photographs, circa 1960s-1970s; 43896 (Box 48, Folder 7)
    - Cranford Construction Company buildings in Park Slope copy negatives, circa 1960s-1970s; 43897 (Box 48, Folder 8)
      V1991.136. Photographs taken by B. Hellmich in 1914-1915. Includes Flatbush Avenue and surrounding blocks in the Park Slope and Prospect Heights neighborhoods of Brooklyn. Copy prints created by EHO and owned by Roger Imperial.
    - Miscellaneous prints and contact sheets, circa 1966-1980s; 43898 (Box 48, Folder 9)
    - Assorted 8"x10" prints, 1970s; 44026 (Box 54, Folder -)
      Includes photographs of Brownstones, residents, community events, and the Brooklyn Union Gas Company's Cinderella projects
    - Historic waterfront copy prints, circa 1970s; 44126 (Box 73, Folder -)
    - Ports and terminals copy prints, circa 1970s; 44127 (Box 73, Folder -)
    - Mural color transparencies and print, circa 1970s; 43899 (Box 48, Folder 10)
    - Mr. Hoecker in Winton #43 automobile in circa 1899 copy print, 1973; 43895 (Box 48, Folder 11)
      V1973.5.1949/b
    - Park Slope Landmark photographs, circa 1973; 44015 (Box 48, Folder 12)
    - Wooden houses photographs, 1975-1988; 44016 (Box 48, Folder 13)
    - BRC and BTTC photographs, circa 1976-1994; 44017 (Box 48, Folder 14)
      Includes Long Island Historical Society (1978), Trinity Church (1978), Carroll Gardens poster (1978), BRC workshop at Con Ed (1989), 39 White Street (Manhattan, 1989), Holdenstein lecture (1994), Workshop/exhibition room (1994)
    - EHO contact sheets returned by the Municipal Art Society of New York, 1979; 44018 (Box 48, Folder 15)
      Includes R74
    - Grand Army Plaza aerial photograph by Jim Kalett, circa 1970s-1980s; 49402 (Box 75, Folder -)
    - Prospect Park South photographs, circa 1980s; 44019 (Box 48, Folder 16)
    - Flatbush walking tour photographs, 1987-1988; 44020 (Box 51, Folder 1)
    - Aerial view contact sheet and negatives, 1988; 44021 (Box 51, Folder 2)
      Brooklyn Botanic Garden, Grand Army Plaza, Gowanus Canal, waterfront, and Park Slope
    - Grand Central Station with Brooklyn Botanic Garden photograph - Prints and negatives, 1989; 44022 (Box 51, Folder 3)
  - Sub-series 4.2: Brooklyn, Historic Preservation, and personal negatives, 1972-1991; 43883; 0.7 Linear Feet in two photographic negative boxes
    The sub-series contains 35mm negative strips taken by Everett Ortner, dating from 1972 to 1991. It includes snapshots and copy negatives of historic images taken by Ortner. The photographs document Brooklyn (especially buildings, landmarks, and festivals), Manhattan (buildings), friends, and travels. Some photographs were taken while Ortner was attending Back to the City conferences in St. Paul (MN) and Hartford (CT). Ortner was an amateur photographer and notes regarding the type of film and cameras he used are sometimes included in the file title of the negatives. Additional copies of some of these images can be found in Sub-series 4.3: Brooklyn and Historic Preservation slides. Of note are photographs of the removal of the "Herald of Peace" statue from the Soldiers' and Sailors' Arch in Grand Army Plaza.
    - Clock Assembly, 8th Avenue and 7th Islands, plus superb picture of Montauk Club, 1972; 43900 (Box 49, Folder 1)
    - Berkeley Window Box Party and Arch (E72), 1972; 43901 (Box 49, Folder 2)
    - Festa - Greenpoint and passport photo copies (A72), 1972; 43902 (Box 49, Folder 3)
    - 272 Berkeley Place interior pix and classic head pix, 1972; 43903 (Box 49, Folder 4)
    - Brooklyn chewing gum and Lincoln Place Block Party (D72), 1972; 43904 (Box 49, Folder 5)
    - Princeton and Buegeleisen anniversary party (B72), 1972; 43905 (Box 49, Folder 6)
    - Harvey and Hazel 50th Anniversary and Triangle Parks publicity (C72), 1972; 43906 (Box 49, Folder 7)
    - Miscellaneous (I73), circa 1973; 43907 (Box 49, Folder 8)
    - Friends (?) and Grand Army Plaza (H73), circa 1973; 43908 (Box 49, Folder 9)
    - Portraits of EHO, EGO, G, and Mara (pets) (H73), 1973; 43909 (Box 49, Folder 10)
    - Shelter Island (A73), 1973; 43910 (Box 49, Folder 11)
    - Shelter Island (E73), 1973; 43911 (Box 49, Folder 12)
    - Brooklyn postcards (including Academy) (B73), 1973; 43912 (Box 49, Folder 13)
    - 234 Lincoln Place for Clem Labine (C73), 1973; 43913 (Box 49, Folder 14)
    - House on Lincoln Place, 8th Avenue houses, and Keystone Everflash (D73), 1973; 43914 (Box 49, Folder 15)
    - Leica CL pix (F72), 1973; 43915 (Box 49, Folder 16)
    - Leica CL pix (G72), 1973; 43916 (Box 49, Folder 17)
    - EGO in front of Adams Houses, Mara (pet dog), and Hoecker car in 1899 (K73), 1973; 43917 (Box 49, Folder 18)
    - Fire Island (F73), 1973; 43919 (Box 49, Folder 19)
    - Machu Picchu I (G73), 1973; 43920 (Box 49, Folder 20)
    - Machu Picchu II (L73), 1973; 43921 (Box 49, Folder 21)
    - Chicago (M73), 1973; 43922 (Box 49, Folder 22)
    - House tour publicity - Model Geraldine Ventrice (M74), 1974; 43923 (Box 49, Folder 23)
    - Customs House 1 (Q74), 1974; 43924 (Box 49, Folder 24)
    - Customs House 2 (K74), 1974; 43925 (Box 49, Folder 25)
    - Brooklyn Academy of Music (BAM) / Triangle #2 (S74), 1974; 43926 (Box 49, Folder 26)
    - Brooklyn Academy of Music (BAM) party with Redgrove (J74), 1974; 43927 (Box 49, Folder 27)
    - Claire's 40 1 (A74), 1974; 43928 (Box 49, Folder 28)
    - Claire's 40 2 (B74), 1974; 43929 (Box 49, Folder 29)
    - Inca in the Window (E74), 1974; 43930 (Box 49, Folder 30)
    - Marshall's summer place (C74), 1974; 43931 (Box 49, Folder 31)
    - Marshall's summer place (D74), 1974; 43932 (Box 49, Folder 32)
    - Flatbush Avenue Festival (Beame (?) and EGO) (L74), 1974; 43933 (Box 49, Folder 33)
    - Brooklyn view from Williamsburgh Savings Bank tower and Van Cortlandt House, Philipse Manor (N74), 1974; 43934 (Box 49, Folder 34)
    - Sleepy Hollow (I74), 1974; 43935 (Box 49, Folder 35)
    - Hudson houses, Poughkeepsie, etc. (P74), 1974; 43936 (Box 49, Folder 36)
    - Flatbush houses, Brooklyn Academy of Music (BAM) painting, Customs House (O74), 1974; 43937 (Box 49, Folder 37)
    - Flatbush houses (Japanese and others) (H74), 1974; 43938 (Box 49, Folder 38)
    - Custom House, Battery Park (R74), 1974; 43939 (Box 49, Folder 39)
    - Hudson tours 1 (F74), 1974; 43940 (Box 49, Folder 40)
    - Hudson tours 2 (G74), 1974; 43941 (Box 49, Folder 41)
    - Montrose Morris and interior of his home / 8th Avenue and Montauk Club / Olmsted and Vaux plan for Prospect Park (H75), circa 1975; 43942 (Box 49, Folder 42)
    - Ports and Terminals copy negs, circa 1975; 43943 (Box 49, Folder 43)
    - Park Slope (Arch, park, Montauk Club details - Konica lens) (L75), 1975; 43944 (Box 49, Folder 44)
    - St. Paul - Endicott Building (Cass Gilbert) (Ilford film) (A75), 1975; 43945 (Box 49, Folder 45)
    - St. Paul (B75), 1975; 43946 (Box 49, Folder 46)
    - St. Paul (C75), 1975; 43947 (Box 49, Folder 47)
    - Night shots of Manhattan from Brooklyn Heights (K75), 1975; 43948 (Box 49, Folder 48)
    - Customs House and Cavaglieri drawings (J75), 1975; 43949 (Box 49, Folder 49)
    - Hartford, Connecticut (D75), 1975; 43950 (Box 49, Folder 50)
    - Hartford, Connecticut (E75), 1975; 43951 (Box 49, Folder 51)
    - Villard Houses - Interior, 1975; 43952 (Box 49, Folder 52)
    - Chicago 1 (F75), 1975; 43953 (Box 49, Folder 53)
    - Chicago 2 (I75), 1975; 43954 (Box 49, Folder 54)
    - Chicago 3 (G75), 1975; 43955 (Box 49, Folder 55)
    - Greenpoint Festa, 1975; 43956 (Box 49, Folder 56)
    - Greenpoint Festa and Marshall's country place, 1975; 43957 (Box 49, Folder 57)
    - Marshall's country place A, 1975; 43958 (Box 49, Folder 58)
    - Marshall's country place B, 1975; 43959 (Box 49, Folder 59)
    - Gardiner Island and port copy negs, 1975; 43960 (Box 49, Folder 60)
    - Woolworth Building - Wemple (T75), 1975; 43961 (Box 50, Folder 1)
    - Minnesota, 1975; 43962 (Box 50, Folder 2)
    - St. Paul, 1975; 43963 (Box 50, Folder 3)
    - St. Paul, 1975; 43964 (Box 50, Folder 4)
    - St. Paul, 1975; 43965 (Box 50, Folder 5)
    - St. Paul, 1975; 43966 (Box 50, Folder 6)
    - St. Paul and Boston, 1975; 43967 (Box 50, Folder 7)
    - Boston and Ellis Island, 1975; 43968 (Box 50, Folder 8)
    - Hallway details and Inca, 1975; 43969 (Box 50, Folder 9)
    - Museum Open House, 1975; 43970 (Box 50, Folder 10)
    - Museum Open House, 1975; 43971 (Box 50, Folder 11)
    - Minox EL pictures, 1976; 43972 (Box 50, Folder 12)
    - EGO portraits, 1976; 43973 (Box 50, Folder 13)
    - 8th Avenue houses repairs (Einhorn and Surgon) and Views from Williamsburgh Savings Bank tower, 1976; 43974 (Box 50, Folder 14)
    - Job: 1006 - Roll No.: 1, 1976; 43975 (Box 50, Folder 15)
    - Job: 1006 - Roll No.: 2, 1976; 43976 (Box 50, Folder 16)
    - Job: 1006 - Roll No.: 2, 1976; 43977 (Box 50, Folder 17)
    - Museum Ball (Minox EL), 1976; 43978 (Box 50, Folder 18)
    - Red Groom's sculpture show at Marlborough Gallery, New York, 1976; 43979 (Box 50, Folder 19)
    - Greenpoint Festa, 1976; 43980 (Box 50, Folder 20)
    - Everett sail and Lower Manhattan, 1976; 43981 (Box 50, Folder 21)
    - Grand Army Plaza (Celestron 1250 mm lens), 1976; 43982 (Box 50, Folder 22)
    - Grand Army Plaza - Removing "Herald of Peace" from Quadriga, 1976; 43983 (Box 50, Folder 23)
    - Brooklyn Botanic Garden - Japanese Hill-and0Pond Garden, circa 1980s; 43984 (Box 50, Folder 24)
    - EHO and two others, circa 1980s; 43985 (Box 50, Folder 25)
    - Home interior?, circa 1980s; 43986 (Box 50, Folder 26)
    - Cass Gilbert's Custom House, 1986; 43987 (Box 50, Folder 27)
    - Federal Hall, 1986; 43988 (Box 50, Folder 28)
    - Abraham Lincoln in Prospect Park / Litchfield / Landmarks hearings / Jewish cemetery in Manhattan / Bryce Canyon and more southwest, circa 1987; 43989 (Box 50, Folder 29)
    - Ladies Miles stuff, 1987; 43990 (Box 50, Folder 30)
    - Brooklyn Botanic Garden - Forsythia Day, 1987; 43991 (Box 50, Folder 31)
    - Majestic Theater under renovation - Fulton Street, 1987; 43992 (Box 50, Folder 32)
    - 359 Broadway (Brady Gallery) / College Place / American Express (Hubert Street) / Western Union (23rd Street and 5th Avenue) / LIRR doors / Mayor Koch election sign (2nd Avenue and 60th Street), 1987; 43993 (Box 50, Folder 33)
    - On-off Broadway #1 (Ricoh FF-AF), 1987; 43994 (Box 50, Folder 34)
    - Mesa Verde and SoHo (one shot of [illegible] journalist at Montauk), 1987; 43995 (Box 50, Folder 35)
    - Flagpole at 42nd Street library / Shaving Jason and Argus in house / 5th Avenue and 42nd Street - northeast corner - Levi Morton house / Oriole and architectural ornamentation - where? / Art deco tower -? / Two bridges from Manhattan scenic, circa 1987; 43996 (Box 50, Folder 36)
    - Snapshots - Madison Square to Weehawken Street, circa 1987; 43997 (Box 50, Folder 37)
    - Washington plaque / Under bridge / 359 Broadway / 42nd Street, 1987; 43998 (Box 50, Folder 38)
    - Children's Aid stuff / Lincoln photo February 1960 by Brody / Harry and Hazel at Coney Island circa 1925? / All copy stuff, 1988; 43999 (Box 50, Folder 39)
    - Children's Aid stuff / Larry Rutyna (?) and brother, circa 1988; 44000 (Box 50, Folder 40)
    - Guastavino Houses - West 78th Street #1 and lower Manhattan from Fulton Landing on a clear day, 1988; 44001 (Box 50, Folder 41)
    - Guastavino Houses - West 78th Street #2 / North and South groups / North side: 121-136, six houses / South side: 118-134, nine houses, 1988; 44002 (Box 50, Folder 42)
    - Fourth Avenue and Flatbush area, 1988; 44003 (Box 50, Folder 43)
    - Indonesians at Hilary Beecher party, 1988; 44004 (Box 50, Folder 44)
    - BRC Broadway tours with Joe Zito / To Mets game with Labines and Mav Shalls (?) / Queensboro Bridge approach / Montauk friends / Degas at Met Museum, 1988; 44005 (Box 50, Folder 45)
    - Constitutional Convention, Poughkeepsie, New York, 1988; 44006 (Box 50, Folder 46)
    - Wooden houses / Washington Avenue / Berkeley Place, 1988; 44007 (Box 50, Folder 47)
    - Navy Yard old officer's houses / Brooklyn Botanic Garden, 1989; 44008 (Box 50, Folder 48)
    - Brooklyn Botanic Garden photo in Grand Central, 1989; 44009 (Box 50, Folder 49)
    - Some India with Claire and EGO and Princes (?) party, 1989; 44010 (Box 50, Folder 50)
    - Old New York pix copied from slides, 1989; 44011 (Box 50, Folder 51)
    - Family party at Levins (?), 1990; 44012 (Box 50, Folder 52)
    - Vermont and Sumi modeling, 1990; 44013 (Box 50, Folder 53)
    - Montauk Club Man of the Year celebration, 1991; 44014 (Box 50, Folder 54)
  - Sub-series 4.3: Brooklyn and Historic Preservation slides, 1959-2005; 43884; 8 Linear Feet in thirteen slide boxes and one slide binder
    The sub-series contains 35mm slides, mostly taken by Everett Ortner, dating from 1959 to 2005. The majority of the slides were used in lectures delivered by Ortner. Files related to these lectures can be found in Series 5: Brooklyn and Historic Preservation lectures. Geographically the slides cover Brooklyn (especially the neighborhood of Park Slope) and Manhattan. They predomidantly feature buildings, as well as festivals (especially the Atlantic Antic and the Giglio Feast of Williamsburg), landmarks, and the waterfront. The sub-series also includes numerous copy slides of historic Brooklyn images. In addition to lecture slides, the subseries contains a small amount of personal photographs.
    Arranged alphabetically by title. Titles were derived from labels found on binders and other boxes that originally housed the slides.
    - Bay Ridge and Fort Hamilton, 1962-1963, 1977; 49463 (Volume Slides by Accession # binder, Folder -)
      V1982.008
    - Brooklyn Botanic Garden, Grand Army Plaza, Prospect Park, 1967-1997; 44027 (Box 55, Folder 1-10)
      Includes Prospect Park Zoo, Prospect Park West, and Pavilion Theater
    - Brooklyn Botanic Garden and Green-Wood Cemetery, 1970-1998; 44028 (Box 55, Folder 11-15)
      Includes Weir-McGovern Greenhouse and Front Street Church/Rectory
    - Brooklyn Historic, 1969-1996; 44029 (Box 56, Folder 1)
      Includes copy slides of 19th and early 20th century images, Prospect Park, breweries, Flatbush Avenue, Williamsburgh Savings Bank tower (interiors, exteriors, and views from the tower), maps, Battle of Long Island, waterfront, Downtown Brooklyn, Myrtle Avenue elevated railroad, and New York Transit Museum
    - Brooklyn Historic 2, 1971-2001; 44030 (Box 56, Folder 2-9)
      Includes copy slides of 19th and 20th century images (some of which were used in the 2005 and the 2007 Brownstone calendars)
    - Brooklyn Lecture, 1972-1988; 44031 (Box 56, Folder 10-14)
      See related lecture notes in Box 38
    - Brooklyn Neighborhoods, 1973-1988; 44032 (Box 56, Folder 14-21)
      Includes Greenpoint, Ditmas Park, Brooklyn Heights, Fort Greene, Williamsburg, other neighborhoods, and Irish Fair in DUMBO (1981)
    - Brooklyn Neighborhoods 2, 1968-2001; 44033 (Box 56, Folder 22-24)
      Includes Williamsburg Festa (Giglio Feast), Atlantic Antic, Greenpoint, Brooklyn Heights, other neighborhoods, and Macy's fireworks
    - Brooklyn Neighborhoods 2, 1968-2001; 44034 (Box 57, Folder 1-13)
    - Brooklyn Nostalgia and Mallification, 1974-2000; 44035 (Box 57, Folder 14-15)
    - Brooklyn Miscellaneous, 1972-2000; 44036 (Box 57, Folder 16-25)
      Includes Williamsburg Festa (Giglio Feast), Atlantic Antic, Buryea House (East New York), Prospect Park Tennis House, Mermaid Parade, Navy Yard Officers' Houses, Sunset Park waterfront, Broadway elevated train, Clinton Hill, Park Slope, churches and cemeteries, and Brooklyn Botanic Garden
    - Brooklyn Miscellaneous, 1972-2000; 44037 (Box 58, Folder 1)
    - Brooklyn Places and Institutions, 1973-1998; 44038 (Box 58, Folder 1-9)
      Includes Grand Army Plaza, Prospect Park, Prospect Park West, Erie Basin, Coney Island amusements, Back to Brooklyn Festival, Long Island Historical Society, Brooklyn Academy of Music (BAM), Brooklyn Post Office and other civic buildings, Wyckoff-Bennett Homestead, Brooklyn Bridge, Fulton Ferry, Brooklyn Heights Promenade (Esplanade), Verrazano Bridge, Jay Street Firehouse, and Sunset Park waterfront
    - Brooklyn Waterfront, 1980-1986; 44039 (Box 58, Folder 9-12)
      Includes Sea Gate, Coney Island, Half Moon Hotel, New York Harbor, Brighton Beach, Bay Ridge, Sheepshead Bay, Manhattan Beach, Kingsborough Community College, Verrazano Bridge, Brooklyn Bridge, 45th Street docks, Italy-Brooklyn boat race, old Brooklyn warehouses, Brooklyn dry dock, Isbrandtsen Terminal, old C.G. Armory, Brooklyn Army Terminal, and docks
    - Broadway (Manhattan), 1976-1988; 44040 (Box 58, Folder 13-24)
    - Broadway (Manhattan), 1976-1988; 44041 (Box 59, Folder 1-4)
    - Brownstone Age, 1975-1990; 44042 (Box 59, Folder 4-7)
    - Brownstone Seminar #1, 1974-2001; 44043 (Box 59, Folder 8-9)
    - Brownstone Style Part 2, 1973-2000; 44077 (Box 67, Folder 11-12)
      Includes Brooklyn Heights, Smith Street, Greenwich Village, Washington Square, St. Luke's Place, Central Park, Upper West Side, and Harlem. See related lecture notes in Box 37.
    - Ellis Island and other slides, 1975-1992; 44044 (Box 59, Folder 9-18)
      Includes Sailors Snug Harbor, OP Sail (July 4, 1976), Statue of Liberty Fireworks (July 4, 1986), July 4th Fireworks (1990), and Tall Ships (1992)
    - FDNY Ladder 114 firehouse (Sunset Park), 1977; 49465 (Volume Slides by Accession # binder, Folder -)
    - Fun, Townhouses, Odds and Ends, etc., 1967-2001; 44045 (Box 59, Folder 18-24)
      Some of these slides were used for a slideshow at a Fisher fundraiser held on May 30, 2000. Includes images of buildings in Brooklyn, Manhattan, Doylestown (PA), Cleveland (OH), Buffalo (NY), Morgantown (WV), Deerfield (MA), West Point (NY), Detroit (MI), and New Harmony (IN). Also includes images of the Atlantic Antic, Williamsburg Festa (Giglio Feast), Coney Island Mermaid Parade, Ellis Island and the East River, Grand Army Plaza and Prospect Park, 272 Berkeley Place dining room, and foreign travel. See related lecture notes in Box 38.
    - Fun, Townhouses, Odds and Ends, etc., 1967-2001; 44046 (Box 60, Folder 1-2)
    - Inside a Brownstone, 1968-1980; 44047 (Box 60, Folder 2-9)
    - Long Island Historical Society - Miss Maud Dilliard in Children's History Room, 1963; 49466 (Volume Slides by Accession # binder, Folder -)
    - Manhattan above 14th Street, 1969-1981; 44048 (Box 60, Folder 10-23)
    - Manhattan above 14th Street 2, 1973-1991; 44049 (Box 60, Folder 24)
    - Manhattan above 14th Street 2, 1973-1991; 44050 (Box 61, Folder 1-10)
    - Manhattan - Canal Street to 14th Street, 1968-2000; 44051 (Box 61, Folder 10-22)